In an earlier domain, we introduced the concept of private IP addresses and their use in the overall IP addressing scheme.
And, since this particular topic is mentioned several times in this course, we will recap those address numbers later.
Two more ranges of IP addresses of note are multicast addresses and reserved addresses. Take a look at this routing table. In particular, I want you to notice this 224.0.0.0 address.
This is the first address in the range of multicast addresses. Multicast addresses are not assigned to devices.
They are used when one device needs to send the same data to multiple devices at once.
The IP address range for multicast IP addresses is any IP address starting with the numbers 224 through 239.
Not seen here is a big range of IP addresses with numbers starting from 240 to 255.
Those are used for experimental purposes, except for this address of 255.255.255.255, which is the overall broadcast address.
Data sent to this address is sent to every device on a network. This is done when, for example, a device needs to know the MAC address of a device with a certain IP address.
It asks, quote unquote, everyone on the network for a match. That is the purpose of the overall broadcast address.